#### Contact

9402684175 (Home) prathap.allu2616@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/prathap08a (LinkedIn) github.com/PrathapAllu (Portfolio)

## Top Skills

C#

Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)

.NET MAUI

## Languages

Telugu (Native or Bilingual)
Hindi (Full Professional)
French (Limited Working)
Tamil (Professional Working)
English (Full Professional)

### Certifications

.NET 7 First Look
Introduction to Generative AI
JSON Essential Training
Introduction to Linux
Create Your Own Chatbot Website
with Open Source LLMs

# Prathap Allu

.Net Full stack developer | Angular | Azure | Technology enthusiastic | Just started on LLM App's

Irving, Texas, United States

# Summary

Full stack .NET Developer with a track record in building web and desktop applications for healthcare, automotive, and retail sectors. Specialized in front-end and back-end development, delivering responsive UIs and optimizing database integration with test-driven methods. Improved system performance, security, and user experience through innovative development practices.

# Experience

Lighthouse Worldwide Solutions Software Engineer August 2023 - Present (1 year 5 months)

data visualization for contamination monitoring, and modified existing Views, View Models and services in MVVM pattern to ensure loose coupling.

•Implemented build validations, managed deployment slots, and rollbacks for a Blazor application, leveraging Azure DevOps for CI/CD pipelines, Azure App Service for staging deployments and Azure Repos for version control and rollbacks.

•Developed new user controls using XAML and Telerik UI, providing dynamic

- •Performed unit testing with MS Test and validated test case scripts, achieving 95% code coverage and accuracy.
- •Continuously contributed towards improving our suite of tools by fixing bugs, writing unit tests and improving documentation all while maintaining excellent coding standards

Onward Technologies Limited .NET Developer August 2021 - July 2022 (1 year)

 As a technical team member, I've been involved in the full software development life cycle, including design, development, planning, automation, and support includes developing RESTful APIs and Web API to interact with SQL Server Database in an Object-Oriented Analysis and Design(OOAD) approach.

- Successfully migrated ASP.NET Core application from IIS 8.5 to Azure.
   Utilized .NET Core, Entity Framework Core, Azure App Services, and
   Application Gateway to achieve requirment. Implemented Azure AD, Key
   Vault, migrated legacy web services to APIs for security, and managed quality
   SSL gateway defects.
- Involved in working with Server side state management using session management state to maintain state among pages.
- Debugged FrontEnd (angular 14) code issues using tools such as nginspector and developer console in browsers.

Cerner Corporation
Software Engineer
July 2019 - August 2021 (2 years 2 months)

Project: Electronic Health Record (EHR) and Patient Registration Implemented advanced analytics and real-time clinical dashboards in Cerner Millennium, enhancing decision-making and patient care. Integrated HL7 (ADT) for performance metrics and FHIR API for comprehensive health data. Developed user-centric interfaces and streamlined patient registration workflows.

## Responsibilities:

- Member of Agile team to support .Net Legacy application built using C#, Winforms, OracleDB, ADO.NET.
- Integrated voice recognition feature by using C# speech recognition library which would detect speech and converted speech to text into our legacy applications to enhance and modernize user experience.
- Enhanced WinForms application that consumes FHIR API and HL7 (ADT) to display key performance indicators and interactive visualization for inpatient entry analytics. Improved user interface for health centers maintaining EHR's.
- Authored classes to support COM objects for interoperability between .Net classes to Java platform with C++ middleware.
- Involved in uplifting of application from VB.net to C#(.Net4.5) and resolved NuGet, .Net compatibility issues during migration.
- Worked in Agile Methodology (Scrum, Project Planning, Retrospection), Risk and Resource Management.
- Train new associates within the team and across the organization.
- Assisted the project team in estimating, analyzing, designing, coding, debugging, testing, and modifying software enhancements and/or new software.

Software Engineer
June 2016 - July 2019 (3 years 2 months)

Project: Geode and CAT 797F Checklist Tool

Involved in development of tool uses C02 laser in the HDI PCB making industries and CAT 797F heavy automobile diagnostic tool.

## Responsibilities:

- Implemented real-time communication protocol using SignalR to enable data exchange in WPF,WCF applications via sockets.
- Managed DevOps for single-page ASP.NET Core web application, Hosted to AWS S3 with Git webhooks for Jenkins CI/CD.
- Enhanced the existing PowerShell scipts for WPF Applications as per customer requirement.
- Used Triggers, Data Binding, Data Templates, Control Template, Routed Events in XAML to create desired User Controls.

## Education

Campbellsville University Masters, Computer Science

Vellore Institute of Technology
Bachelor of Technology, Electronics and Communication Engineering